Guide to the Montana State Prison records 1864-1974
Montana Historical Society
- Board Of State Prison Commissioners
  - Prisoners Records
    - Parole files: Bernard L. Harvey, Donald Robert Hay, Thomas D. (T.D.) Hayes, Stole Headcarrier, Henry C. Hedrick, Norman L. Heffelfinger, L.B. Henry, Hilario Hernandez, Antonio Herrera, Joseph A. Herring Jr., Mack Hickerson, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/5)
    - Parole files: Lawrence E. Hill and Glen Nelson, Archie Hinkle, David William Hinkle, William Hissong, Charles W. Hixson, Charles Camp Hixon, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/6)
    - Parole files: Russell Hodge, Fred W. Hodgson, William Hogue, Everett Norman Holden, Walter Wardsey Holcomb, Jewel Holland, Ray Holland, Pat Hollingsworth, Russell Hollister, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/7)
    - Parole files: D.A. Hollowell, Adam Holzer, Ruben Holzworth, Harold H./Harry L./Harvey Hoover, Lloyd Clinton Hoover, Louis R. Hoppe, Clifford Horner, Frank Houghton, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/8)
    - Parole files: Golden G. Howard, John C. Howard, Ernest C. Hudson, H.H. Huffman, Arthur Hughes, James M. Hughes, Frank J. Humbert Jr., James M. Humphrey, Arnold H. Hunt, Harold N. Hunt, Perry Hunt, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/9)
    - Parole files: John Leo Hurnick, Geroge Hyat, Claude Larud and Floyd Clark, Joseph Inderie Sr., Hugh Ingersoll, Jessie W. Ingram and Walter Pipinich, Harry Irby, Earl W. Isbill, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/10)
    - Parole files: Fred A. Jackson, Harry Jackson, Emmet James, Emmett Harrington, Albert Chester Jamieson, George E. Jarvis, George R. Jeffers, Si Jefferson, Henry Lee Jenkins, W.C. Jenkins, Willis W. Jennings, Harvey Jensen, James Jensen, Arthur Jeschke, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/11)
    - Parole files: Joseph Jocque, Rufus Lewis, Errett Johnson, Charles Johnson, Eugene Johnson, Harvey Johnson, Eugene H. Johnson, Helge Johnson, Helge John Johnson, James Darrell Johnson, John Johnson, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/12)
    - Parole files: Marvin (Mike) Johnson, Robert H. Johnson, Walter Leland Johnson, Warren E. Johnson, Bill Victor Johnston, Charles Jones, Edward Jones, Henry Jones, Oscar Jorgerson, Frank/Francis Joscum, Della/Delia Joseph, Ed Judge, Thomas Cleary, Thomas Judge, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/13)
    - Parole files: Rudolph L. Karlin, Edward Kastner, William Keane, Harry Kearns, Dewey Keller, Harry Kelly, James Roy Kelsey, Leo Kennedy, William L. Kennedy, Morris Paul Kendall, Andrew Kenworthy, Bill Kerchel, Jacob Kerner, Jerry King, Adam Ketter/Kidder, Emmett Keyes, Thomas Kilgallion/Kilgallan(on), Isaac Killian, Paul C. Kimmerle, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/14)
    - Parole files: Virgil King, Fred Kingsland, Harry Kinney, Clyde Kipp, Geroge Kipp, James Kirwan, George W. Klass, J.A. Kline, Pat Kline, Pete Knight, Clarence Knopel, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/15)
    - Parole files: Leonard Joe Koerber, Tom Corry (alias Tom Kotsiakes), Frank Krone, Hugo Kuhn, Michael Kurry, Erol B. Labadie, Ernest LaCasse, Joe LaCount, Ernest LeCounte, John Baptiste Ladue, Ben/Dan LaFountain/LaFountaine, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 75/16)
    - Parole files: R.V. Lake, Woodrow Southard Lambert, Alex Lamoose, Fred Lancaster, Walter Lapier, Roland Larson, David Latimer, Fred F. Laurent, Harold Lauries, Leonard LaVallie, Flora/Florence Lawrence, Charles H, Lawton, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/1)
    - Parole files: Clyde Leaverton, Leonard Ledo, Lyle Leigh, Julio Leos, Aimee Eleanor and Dale Thomas Lepsey, A.W. Leslie, Mike Letz, James C. Lewis, Tom Lewis, Dominic/Domacito Lewwues, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/2)
    - Parole files: Harold O. Linaberry, Robert E. Lindeman, Jack Lister, Charles Little, Little Whirl Wind, William Littlefield, Harry Logan, Ralph Longabach, Steven Loomis, John Lowe Jr., John Lugo, Caludio Luna, William Lundi, Albert L. Lundvall, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/3)
    - Parole files: R.O. Lunke, E.G. DeVaul, Frank Luppino, John Mabry, Chester Maggard, Edward Mahoney, Ben Mahr, David Mahseelah, Fred Malatorr, Edith Marsh, Thomas Martell, Eugene Martenson, Frank Martin, Joe Martin, Jim Martinez, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/4)
    - Parole files: Joseph Martinson, Eli J. Martin, Ed Mason, L.M. Spencer, Charles Mathieson, Isadore Martinez, Brien-Antone Matt, Dominick and Davis Matt, George Matt, Wilfred Matt, Woodrow J. Matt, Oswald H. Mattfeldt, Hugh Mattfeldt, L.A. McAllister, Ned McAllister, Gideon McBride, Wayne McAnn, Floyd McClure, Harold P. McLure, Robert J. McCollim, William McCollum, Elmer McConaha, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/5)
    - Parole files: James McConville, William McCracken, I.F. McCully, Mona May McCully, Kirby McCusker, Harold Stotler McElfresh, Cecil Floyd McElroy, L.D. “Happy” McFadden, Sarty McGeeley, Jesse R. McGinnis, Lester McGrath, W.R. McGraw, Leslie McHoes, G.E McHoes, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/6)
    - Parole files: Frederick McIntosh, Lewis F. McKenzie, W.J. McLaren, Harvey E. McLaughlin, Daniel E McLean, Angus McLeod (alias Amos McLeod), James Harker McMahon, Sam J. McNary, Theodore McPherson, Andrew/Andy McQuay, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/7)
    - Parole files: George Meakins (alias V.W. Evans), M.J. Meany (Frank Keyes, Munroe Keyes), Dan Medicine Horse, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/8)
    - Parole files: Delores Paceho Mendoza, Thomas Merryfield, George R. Meserve, Stanley Michael, James M. Mickey, Jasper M. Mickey, Birl Miller, Frank J. Miller, Fred Miller, J. (Jack/John) C. Miller, John Sam Miller, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/9)
    - Parole files: Marvin Miller, William Morgan Miller, Donald M. Mitchell, Harold B. Mitchell, Henry Mitchell, William Mohan, R.J. Monroe, Simon Montez, Adrian Eugene Moody, Chester A. Moore, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/10)
    - Parole files: Roy Moore, Sam Moore, Teddie Moore, W.D. Moore, Charles Moquist, Carlos Luna, Tony Morello, Eugene P. Morgan, Lewis A. Morgan, Ray Morgan, Forest Morigeau, Arthur B. Morrow, William N. Mortimer, Solomon Mosquito, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/11)
    - Parole files: Leonard L. Motari, Francis Mothershead, Joseph M. Mowatt, Edward W. Meuhlhousen, Neil Mulcaster, James W. Mulligan, Matthew McMullen (alias James Murphy), Muriel Murphy Newman, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/12)
    - Parole files: C.C. Murray, E.L. Murray, John Tabish, Clarence Myhre, Gilbert Nadler, Mike Negrete, Bernice Levins Nelms Charles A. Nelson, Emmet Nelson, Gilbert Nelson, Glen Nelson, Lewis Nelson and Frank Rudolph, William B. Nelson, J.A. Nelton, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/13)
    - Parole files: Frank J. Nevills, Louis Newrobe, Floyd Newman, John Newman, William Newman and Muriel Murphy, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/14)
    - Parole files: S.T. Nedeau and George Nicoloff, Paul C. Nitschke, George Nordby, Harold G. Norris, Clarence Norville, George Nulliner, Lynn M. Nye, Donald O’Brien, Jack O’Brien, Larry O’Brien, William (Billy) O’Brien, Michael O’Connor, Tom O’Connor, A.B. Ogden, Nels Ogland, Herber O’Green, Thomas O’Hara, James Olmstead, Floyd Edward Olson, John Olson, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 76/15)
    - Parole files: Lyle O’Neil, Hugh John O’Neill, Chris Opsol, Brenirlaw Orlowski (alias Tom Arlow), Laurence Oulette, Savas Pantelides, William G. Pappas, Fred Pariseau, Daniel Parker, Joe E. Parrish, Harold Parson, Louis Pastor, Edward J. Patalas, Lazell Patrick, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/1)
    - Parole files: Martin Pavich, Walter F. Pearl, Joseph Pearson, Ben E. Pederson, Frank (Jack) Peelman, Frank Pellizari, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/2)
    - Parole files: Joe Peltchie, Albert Peoples, Leo Phalen, E.V. Phillips, Eugene Wents Phillips, L.R. Phillips, Vesper E. Phillips, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/3)
    - Parole files: Patrick A. Pierre, Gilbert Pilcher, John Dunn, Ray Pilkington, Earl Pillsbury, Lee Ping, Fred A.R. Pinnow, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/4)
    - Parole files: Frank Pirker, J.E. Porter, E.R. Powers, Emil Z. Powers, L.W. Powers, Kimball Price, Mrs. Laura (Floyd) Priest, Elmer Primm, Robert Pryor, Raymond Probert, Clarence E. Proper, Thomas A. Prout, Carl Purock, Clarence Poor and Russell Quakenbush, Estella Quinn, John Quintana, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/5)
    - Parole files: Paul Raines, Keith Randolph, Martha Ratkovich, Harley Paul Ravencroft, Frank Raymond, Hugo J. Raymond, Eugene Ready, Michel Redcrow, Jasper Redrobe, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/6)
    - Parole files: J.R. Reece, Buster A. Reed, L.E. Reed, Robert L. Reed, Clyde Reeves, Claude Reynolds, Frank W. Rhodes, Joseph K. Richards, Roy R. Richmyer, Petro Rico, John Rife, Thomas J. Riley, William J. Riley, Otto Ristoe, Juan Rivera, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/7)
    - Parole files: Charles P. Spinharney, Ray Robbins, Samuel Roberson, William F. Roberts, A.E. Robinson, Claude Robinson, Louis Rocheleau, Alvin E. Rogers, Jack Rodgers (alias James J. Rogers), Alma Jane Roebuck, Richard Rogers, William Rogers, Jack Rohr, Edwin Rollins and David Hoff, Sostenes Romero Jr., Anthony Ross, Cleo Ross, Herman Rounds, Wilbur G. Rowe, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/8)
    - Parole files: Oscar Rowland, Darrel A. Rubens, Eli Rudman Jr., Roy Cecil Rumsey and Roy Howard Scott, W.H. Rush, Charles E. Rusk, Clement Ryan, Thomas “Buddy” Ryan, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/9)
    - Parole files: Robert Salter, John H. Sanders, Joe Santarosa, Charles Sargent, William Saunders, Benjamin T. Savage, L.W. Scarbrough, George Schaffer, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/10)
    - Parole files: Charles Allen Scharf, E.J. Sheid, Ed Scheid, Fred Schindler, John W. Schmidt, John Schooley, Mervin David Schreiner, Henry (Bum) Schubert, Ray Shumaker, Peter Schwind, Sam J. Scott, Clifford Sederburg, Finley Sensiba, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/11)
    - Parole files: William Shea, Nelson J. Sheldon, Robert Sherrill, Frank Sherry (alias F.R. Ferguson), James Sherwood, Al Shibley, Edward Louis Shipp, Theodore Shropshire and Myrele L. Bauer, A.N. Shrout, Nelson Shrout (Lewis Yankoff and Robert Chapin), Carl Shultz (alias Paul Stevens, J.P. Stevens), P.C. Stephens, Dehlia C. Schultz, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/12)
    - Parole files: William James Shupe, Herman Sieben, John Henry Sieben, George Sime, Margaret Simich, Haskell L. Simmons, Calvin Simon, Dean Sims, Carl Skeie, C.C. Skidmore, Julio Sleviea, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/13)
    - Parole files: John Sydylowski, Cecil B. Smith, Charles F.A. Smith, Harry Smith, James J. Smith, John L. Smith, J.L. Smith, Leslie M. Smith, Milton H. Smith (true name Harry W. O’Donnell), Raymond Smith, T.R. Delaney, William Snyder, W.L. Snyder, Dale Soapes, Joseph Kane, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/14)
    - Parole files: Jack Soda, Arthur T. Soderstrom, Fred Sohl (or Sols), Francis Solem, Chris B. Bueno, Francis L. Soria, J.D. Sorrel, Robert J. Souhrada, Howard Spalding, Elmer Spencer, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/15)
    - Parole files: Charles P. Spinharney, Ed St. Germaine, Frank Stack, Paul Eugene Stamper, Orville Stanberry, Jack Riley, R.J. Standish, John Stanley, Norman H. Stapleton, Carl F. Starke, F.L. Stephens, Otto Stenborg, Clem Stephens, Charles Stevens, Ralph Stevens, Roy Stevens, Russell M. Stevens, Theodore Mike Stevens, William Stevens, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 77/16)
    - Parole files: May Stevenson (many aliases), William Stewart, Frank Stone, Charles Stopher, Robert W. Stricklin, Mar Suey, Henry J. Suhr, Fred D. Sullivan, Tom Surle, Albert Swain, John Sweeney, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/1)
    - Parole files: Robert Taintor, E. Milio Meresse, Loren Talbert, George Taliaferro, Fred Tarr, Joseph Tarr, James Tate, Buck Taylor, Eugene Taylor, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/2)
    - Parole files: H.A. Taylor, Ray Taylor, Sylvester Taylor, Cecil E. Thayer, Harry D. Thomas, Leonard Thomas, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/3)
    - Parole files: Ed Thompson, George Thompson, Harry Thompson (alias Vernie Rich), Ray Thompson, Wallace F. Thrall, Kenneth Eugene Timms, Keith Tobias, Jerome R. Todak (and Charles W. Weston), Albert R. Tomlin, Adolph Torgeson, H.N. Tracy, Alexander Traylor, Luke Traynor, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/4)
    - Parole files: Beryl Treat, Joe M. Trombley Jr., Walter Trotchie, Charles Robert Andrew Tucker, Leland Tucker, Ambrose Turkovich, Harry Turner, George Gilbert Van Auken, Leonard N. Johnson, George Vandervich, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/5)
    - Parole files: George Van Laningham, John Vannoy (Jack Sweeton), Jack Van Ray, Guillermo Vasquez, Charles Vaughn, Alfred Venturini, Frank Vetal, William Vey, E.J. Vicain, Hans Vegoren, Frank Vinn, Edward W. Virtue, William Vitalis, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/6)
    - Parole files: Robert B. Waddell, Robert Waining (alias Bobbie Vance), Sidney W. Clark, Otis L. Waite, Milo Walker (and James Lewis), Gladys Walks-on-top, James E. Wall, Everett Walters, Richard H. Ward, William Ward, Edward P. Warner, Albert Warner, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/7)
    - Parole files: George Washington, Robert B. Wasson, Earl Watson, Douglas Watters, Charles Weasel Head, Mary A. Weathers, Joseph W. Webber, Adam Weber, Jack Weber, David Mason Weed, Frank Weeden, August Wegner, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/8)
    - Parole files: Buer Weight, Thomas Well Known, Curtis W. West, Fred Westrope, Charles W. Weston, Eddie Wheeler, Charles White, Frank White, Walter S. White, Will White, Frank Whitlock, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/9)
    - Parole files: Walter J. Whitney, Thomas Whitten, Frederick Weise, Jack W. Wilborn, Stanley Wilkins (alias Oscar Miller, Martin Gleason, and Stanley Przyblski), Ralph D. Wilks (alias Jack Wilks), N.A. Willis, Bob C. Williams, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/10)
    - Parole files: Claude Williams, Dora Williams, Ed Williams, Hall Williams, William Williams, Richard Willis, Arvil Chester Wilson, Alfred Eugene Wilson, Frank Wilson, Fred C. Wilson, Nelson Maybell, Maxwell Bruce Wilson, Charles J. Wiltermood, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/11)
    - Parole files: Dan Winegarden, Guy S. Winters, Peter Witkaukas, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/12)
    - Parole files: Ernest Wittenburg, Charles Wolfe, Wong Jan Yen, Charles Wood, Earl Stanley Woodbury, James Woodlin, John Woods, Lawrence C. Woodward, Jerry Wooten, E.B. Worley, Steve Worley, Charles M. Wyatt, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/13)
    - Parole files: Henry Yaunez, Yee Gar Young, Leo Yellowrobe, Billy Don Yoss, Orvol Young, W.W. Young, Carl William Zepp, Earnest and Mike Zielke, 1895-1960 (Box-folder 78/14)
    - Parole report cards: A - Dib, 1915-1955 (Box 79)
    - Parole report cards: Dic - Hus, 1915-1955 (Box 80)
    - Parole report cards: I - Nich, 1915-1955 (Box 81)
    - Parole report cards: Nico - Smith, F., 1915-1955 (Box 82)
    - Parole report cards: Smith, G. - Z, 1915-1955 (Box 83)
    - Alphabetical listing of prisoners in suspended sentence files, undated (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Suspended sentence files: A - Bec, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Suspended sentence files: Bel - Bur, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Suspended sentence files: C - D, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Suspended sentence files: E - H, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/5)
    - Suspended sentence files: J - L, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/6)
    - Suspended sentence files: Ma - Men, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/7)
    - Suspended sentence files: Mer - O, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/8)
    - Suspended sentence files: Pa - Pe, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/9)
    - Suspended sentence files: Pi - R, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/10)
    - Suspended sentence files: S, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/11)
    - Suspended sentence files: T - Y, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 84/12)
    - Suspended sentence orders, 1913-1937 (Volume 63-68)
    - Suspended sentence orders, 1938-1955 (Box-folder 84/13-84/15)
  - Miscellany
    - Blank forms and lists of procedures (re receiving and discharging prisoners at Montana State Prison and patients at Montana State Hospital; paroles; escapes; revocation and restoration of statutory and earned "good time"; termination of sentence; transfers between institutions; interstate compact cases; restoriation of civil rights; Indian convicts; deportations; and general form letters), 1959 (Box-folder 84/16)
    - Interviews of prisoners John Mazzano, Richard Dixon, Jacob Wertin, William Settles, James Meddles, F.W. Beeskove, and Charles Smith No. 1 with Attorney General Albert J. Galen and Warden Frank Conley concerning allowance of "good time", undated (Box-folder 84/17)
    - Suspended sentence report cards: A - G, 1915-1952 (Box 85)
    - Suspended sentence report cards: H - Pa, 1915-1952 (Box 86)
    - Suspended sentence report cards: Pe - Z, 1915-1952 (Box 87)
    - Oversized Materials, undated (Box 89)
- United States Penitentiary. Montana Territory
  - General Correspondence
    - Outgoing correspondence (re housing prisoners), 1875 (Box-folder 88/1)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - A-D (correspondents include U.S. Attorney General Williams, Lewis and Clark County Commissioners and C. L. Dahler re housing prisoners and leasing space in court rooms), 1874-1876 (Box-folder 88/2)
  - Financial Records
    - Expense Journal, 1886-1889 (Box-folder 88/3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Leases (re space in Lewis and Clark and Madison County court houses), 1874-1875, undated (Box-folder 88/4)
    - Memoranda of agreement between Governor Benjamin Potts and William F. Wheeler, U.S. Marshall (re operation of the penitentiary at Deer Lodge), 1874-1877 (Box-folder 88/5)
    - Miscellany (re sale of land by Deer Lodge Townsite Company for construction of penitentiary), 1864-1868 (Box-folder 88/6)
  - Reports
    - Directors' report, 1873 (Box-folder 88/7)
    - Physician's report, 1873 (Box-folder 88/8)
    - Warden's Office report, 1873 (Box-folder 88/9)
    - U.S. Grand Jury report on Deer Lodge Penitentiary conditions, 1878 (Box-folder 88/10)
  - Miscellany
    - Inventories of penitentiary property, 1878, undated (Box-folder 88/11)
    - Rules and Regulation (for physicians, guards, contractors and prisoners), undated (Box-folder 88/12)
    - Miscellaneous (reconstruction of the penitentiary at Deer Lodge; includes oversize material, see map case), 1868-1869 (Box-folder 88/13)